A Calendar of The Jefferson Papers of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Dated Materials
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, COVER LEAVES FOR PROPOSALS AND RECOMMENDATIONS FOR WORKMEN AND UNDERTAKERS AT THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA., [1818-1820]; AD. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
  - W. H. WILMER to HUGH NELSON, Washington, D. C., [1818-1823?].; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Letter of introduction for Monsieur Calvo who wishes to apply for position at Central College.
    [1592]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond., 1819 January 1.; ALS. 2 pp. #201. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: Cabell 145-146; B of R VI 59 (MS. in DLC).
    Center of white population in Virginia, calculated to determine best site for the University.
    [1593]
  - A. MACDONALD, Philadelphia, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 4.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #38-745.
    Applies for position as amanuensis or humble servant in any capacity.
    [1594]
  - THOMAS COOPER, Philadelphia, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 5.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Acknowledges receipt of [Rockfish Gap] Report. Workmen for the University. T. J.'s health. Mentions William Short and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [1595]
  - WILSON CARY NICHOLAS, PROMISSORY NOTE to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1819 January 6.; ADS. 1 pp. #2343. Endorsed by T. J.
  - ERASMUS STRIBLING, Staunton, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 January 6.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommendation of Dabney Cosby, bricklayer.
    [1596]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 7.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 146-149.
    Cabell's labors in the General Assembly on behalf of the University Bill. T. J.'s health. References to John Brockenbrough, Chancellor John W. Green, Thomas C. Holmes, W. C. Nicholas, Mr. Pannel, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., Spencer Roane, Mr. Slaughter, John Taliaferro, Samuel Taylor, Chancellor [Creed] Taylor, and Philip Thompson.
    [1597]
  - JOHN WAUGH, Staunton, to ALEXANDER GARRETT, Charlottesville., 1819 January 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    [1598]
  - JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Washington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 8.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Acknowledging receipt of Tracy's Political Economy and of the Rockfish Gap Report. Inquiry about T. J.'s health.
    [1599]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 18.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 149-152.
    University Bill passes the House of Delegates with Central College fixed as the site. Various methods of determining the center of population favor Central College. Cabell's recent illness. References to Briscoe G. Baldwin, Dabney Carr, Armistead Holmes, and James Hunter.
    [1600]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 21.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 152-153.
    Progress of the University Bill in the Senate. Bill to connect the eastern and western waters. Cabell's ill-health. References to Judge John Coalter, George Hay, Armistead Holmes, Chapman Johnson, Alfred Powell, John Taliaferro, and Philip Thompson.
    [1602]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [THOMAS] COOPER., 1819 January 22.; ALS. 1 pp. RG-1/3/3.822.
    T. J. writes to Cooper informing him of favorable action by the Delegates in passing the bill to establish the University of Virginia and notes that he counts on Cooper in the spring.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to RICHARD DUKE, near Lindsay's Store., 1819 January 24.; ALS. 1 pp. #6286.
    Duties of Proctor of Central College. Nelson Barksdale suited for part of duties, but Alexander Garrett recommends Duke for other duties. To begin when Legislature approves University. See item 1601, 1819 January 20.
    [2947]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN HARTWELL COCKE., 1819 January 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Cocke Papers, #3184.
    Requesting him to come to Monticello because of business of extreme urgency.
    [1604]
  - EDMUND BACON to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1819 January 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Trip to the West. Market wagon.
    [2948]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 153.
    Passage of the University Bill. Cabell's illness. References to John Coalter, Chapman Johnson, and Edward Watts.
    [1603]
  - ALEXANDER GARRETT, [Charlottesville], to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 January 26.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    James Dinsmore agrees to work by Latrobe's price book. Passage of University Bill in Senate.
    [1605]
  - DABNEY COSBY, Staunton, to JOHN BOWYER, Richmond., 1819 January 28.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Asks for recommendation to assist his application for employment at Central College.
    [1606]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond., 1819 January 28.; ALS. 1 pp. #201. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: Cabell 154; B of R VI 59 (MS. in DLC).
    Passage of the University Bill. Need for extensive funds to execute the plan.
    [1607]
  - SAMUEL CARR, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 1.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231. Enclosure: AD. 1 pp.
    Recommends George Watson as anatomy professor; list of trustees of University of Pennsylvania who might recommend him. Success of the University Bill. Need for further funds. Recommends Dabney Cosby as mechanic. Appropriation of money for primary schools. Mentions Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., and Francis Gilmer.
    [1608]
  - THOMAS COOPER, Philadelphia, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 2.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Salary offered by Visitors too small; will hold decision for final offer. Important law suit pending in United States Circuit Court prevents leaving in October.
    [1609]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 4.; ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed by Cabell 155-159, misdated as of 4 December.
    Advises against moving now for the derelict portion of the School Fund. Copy of reports on the navigation of the James and on connection of eastern and western waters. Sketch of services rendered by the following friends of the University: William Brockenbrough, William H. Brodnax, Francis T. Brooke, Samuel Carr, John Coalter, [Francis W.?] Gilmer (author of essays signed "a Virginian"), John W. Green, George Hay, Armistead Holmes, Garrett Minor, Wilson C. Nicholas, George Nicholson, Mr. Pannel, the Rev. Mr. Rice (author of essay signed "Crito"), Mr. Ritchie, Judge Spencer Roane, James Robertson, JF., Mr. Scott, Captain Slaughter, Mr. Stannard, John Taliaferro, Chancellor [Creed] Taylor, Philip Thompson. Mentions also William S. Archer, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., and James Madison. (Thirteen lines made illegible, probably prior to publication of N. F. Cabell's book).
    [1610]
  - JOHN BROWN, Spring Farm, Va., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 8.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommendation of Dabney Cosby for work at University of Virginia.
    [1611]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 8.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 159-161.
    Revenue of the Literary Fund not equal to appropriations.
    [1612]
  - JAMES P. PRESTON. COMMISSION to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1819 February 13.; DS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Seal. RG-1/3/3.761.
    T. J.'s commission as Visitor of the University of Virginia.
    [1613]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 15.; ALS. 3 pp. #2791. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: Cabell 161-163.
    Appointment of James Breckenridge, Joseph Cabell, John Hartwell Cocke, Chapman Johnson, James Madison, and Robert B. Taylor as Visitors of the University of Virginia. Cabell's health. Untrue report that Cabell is to go to Europe to seek professors. Advises delay in opening the University until sufficient buildings are ready. References to Samuel Taylor, Armistead Holmes, [Samuel] Carr, and Henry St. George Tucker.
    [1614]
  - THOMAS APPLETON, Leghorn, Italy. CONTRACT for UNIVERSITY with Michele and Giacomo Raggi., 1819 February 17.; DS. 4 pp. #9737-d. Endorsed by T. J. Notarized by Thomas F. B. Donati. Certified by Edward Swords, Chancellor, U. S. Consulate.
    Contract for sculpture (marble columns) to be done at the University of Virginia.
    [1615]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond., 1819 February 19.; ALS. 1 pp. #201. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: Cabell 164-165; B of R VI 59 (MS. in DLC).
    Pleasure at choice of the Visitors: James Breckenridge, Robert B. Taylor, John Hartwell Cocke, Cabell, Chapman Johnson, James Madison, and T. J. Construction to be undertaken at University. Mentions Thomas Cooper.
    [1616]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN HARTWELL COCKE, Bremo., 1819 February 19.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Cocke Papers, #3184.
    Inviting Cocke to travel with him to the Board of Visitors' meeting at James Madison's. Mentions Joseph Cabell, Colonel Lindsay, and David Watson.
    [1617]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 22.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 165-167.
    Meeting of the Board of Visitors of University; appointment of Dr. Cooper one of great delicacy and importance; recommends delay in opening until several eminent professors are secured. Difficulties in securing adequate funds from the Assembly. References to James Breckenridge, John Hartwell Cocke, Isaac Coles, James Madison, Robert B. Taylor, and David Watson.
    [1618]
  - THOMAS APPLETON, Leghorn, Italy. DRAFT on JOHN HOLLINS, Baltimore., 1819 February 25.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: B of R VIII 23 (MS. in DLC). #2737-a.
    Draft on Hollins in favor of Thomas Perkins, drawn for account of T. J. (Expenses incurred for the Raggi Brothers in purchase of marble for University).
    [1619]
  - JAMES P. PRESTON, Council Chamber, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1819 February 27.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #7254-a.
    Appointment as Visitor of University.
    [2949]
  - WILLIAM ROSCOE, Liverpool, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 February 28.; ALS. File draft. 2 pp. Photostat. Original owned by City of Liverpool Public Library. #5128-a.
    Submits for comment his pamphlets on the opening of the Liverpool Botanic Gardens, and on penal jurisprudence and the reformation of criminals. Mentions his life of Leo the Tenth, and Beccaria's Essay on Crimes and Punishments.
    [2950]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, RECORD OF MEEETING OF VISITORS OF CENTRAL COLLEGE, 1819 February.; AD. 2 pp. #38-111.
    [1620],
    1819, March 1.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL., 1819 March 1.; ALS. 3 pp. #201. Endorsed by T. J. Partly printed: Cabell 167-169; B of R VI 59 (MS. in DLC).
    Report to the Governor and Council of the Board of Visitors meeting. Progress of negotiations with Thomas Cooper. Denies rumors of Cooper's intemperance. University finances. Mentions Correa da Serra.
    [1620]
  - JOHN ADAMS to [THOMAS JEFFERSON]., 1819 March 2.; L. 1 pp. Copy in the hand of T. J. #3216. Printed: B of R VIII 13 (MS. in DLC).
    Praising Destutt de Tracy's Treatise on Political Economy.
    [1621]
  - JAMES BULLOCK, Lynchburg, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 3.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommendation for David White, plasterer.
    [1622]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to [SIMON] CHAUDRON., 1819 March 3.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat, #1243. Original owned by Miss Estelle Chaudron. Printed: B of R VI 79 (MS. in DLC).
    Best wishes on his removal to the Tombigbee River.
    [1623]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to THOMAS COOPER, Philadelphia., 1819 March 3.; ALS. 2 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Tentative offer to Cooper. Final offer must await Board of Visitors meeting. Stoves for faculty residences.
    [1624]
  - WILLIAM S. REID, JOHN M. GORDON, GEORGE CABELL, and JOHN BULLOCK, Lynchburg., 1819 March 3.; DS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommendations of David White, plasterer.
    [1625]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. PLAN OF LAWN WITH ROTUNDA., 1819 March 3-19.; Ink. Scale: 40' = 1". Paper BD. 27 1/4 x 12 3/4 in. #171.
    N-306 was cut from this piece to permit substitutions; see also N-305, N-369.
    [N-366, K-30]
  - CHARLES JOHNSTON, Lynchburg, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 4.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommends David White, plasterer.
    [1626]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond., 1819 March 6.; ALS. 1 pp. #201. Endorsed by T. J. Printed: Cabell 170.
    Advertisement concerning the University to be put in the Enquirer.
    [1627]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 8.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Partly printed: Cabell 170-172.
    State funds for the University. The Literary Fund. Professorship offered to Thomas Cooper. References to John Hartwell Cocke, Isaac Coles, Alexander Garrett, James Madison, and James P. Preston.
    [1628]
  - ARCHIBALD STUART, Staunton, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 9.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Congratulations on law establishing the University. Recommends Dabney Cosby as bricklayer. Conspiracy of Messrs. Jordan, Brown, Hawkins, and Darst, to get monopoly of brickwork at the University. Request from Messrs. Tucker and Kinney for papers in Jefferson's possession.
    [1629]
  - CHRISTOPHER HUDSON, Mount Air, Va., to T. J, Monticello., 1819 March 10.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommendation of David White, plasterer.
    [1630]
  - DAVID WHITE. PLASTERER'S BID., 1819 March 10.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Prices for plastering at the University.
    [1631]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to DABNEY CARR., 1819 March 11.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Advertisement (for workmen for the University?) for Winchester newspaper.
    [1632]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 12.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 173-174.
    Advertisement for workmen for the University inserted in the Enquirer. Alexander Garrett's draft on Literary Fund will be honored. Importance of securing Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough as proctor. Cabell's health improved. Mentions Mary Cabell, Mr. Montcarel, and Wilson C. Nicholas.
    [1633]
  - THOMAS COOPER, Philadelphia, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 13.; ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Unlikely that Europeans will come to teach at the University of Virginia at income inferior to that common in this country. Terms under which he will go to the University. Mentions Nathaniel Bowditch, Parker Cleaveland, Zaccheus Collins, Dr. Holly, Dr. Meade, Mr. McNulty, Robert Patterson, Charles W. Peale, Mr. Shaw, and John Vaughan.
    [1634]
  - WILSON CARY NICHOLAS, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 13.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Stresses abilities of Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough. Urges he be secured as proctor to oversee construction. Mentions Alexander Garrett.
    [1635]
  - DABNEY COSBY, Staunton, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 14.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Mr. Bolinger's prices for boring logs.
    [1636]
  - LEVI TAYLOR, Baltimore, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia., 1819 March 16.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Application for work as stonecutter.
    [1637]
  - JAMES C. FISHER, Edward Burd, John Vaughan, John Read, Philadelphia, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia., 1819 March 17.; DS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommending Richard Ware as a carpenter for the University of Virginia.
    [1638]
  - M. M. RANDOLPH, Tuckahoe, to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Richmond., [1819] March 17.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommendation for Daniel R. Calverly, painter, for work at Central College
    [1639]
    [1646]
    , 1819 March 23.
  - CHRISTOPHER BRANCH, Manchester, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 20.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Application for carpentry work at the University.
    [1640]
  - ROBERT MILLS, Baltimore, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 20.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommending Richard Ware, master carpenter, to Nelson Barksdale, Proctor of the University of Virginia. Progress on Washington Monument.
    [1641]
  - JACOB H. WALKER, Smyrna, Del., to NELSON BARKSDALE, Charlottesville., 1819 March 20.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Application for work as carpenter. Asks advance over wages in Matthew Carey's price book.
    [1642]
  - JOHN BROCKENBROUGH, Richmond, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 22.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommends Mr. Hickey, plasterer, for University.
    [1643]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 22.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommends Mr. Hickey as plasterer. Mentions Mr. Haxall, former employer, and [John] Brockenbrough.
    [1644]
  - JOHN PARHAM, Philadelphia, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia, or to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 23.; LS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Offers to do carpentry work at the University. Matthew Carey's price book not known. Those now in use belong to the new and old Carpenters' Hall. Mentions W. Duane, Captain Dunlap, Captain Hardy, Thomas Pratt, Dr. Pilmore, W. Strickland, Burton Wallace, and Dr. Wylie.
    [1645]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Varina, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 23.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Introducing Mr. Calverly. Delayed in Richmond. Wheat crop, flowers, bushes, and birds at Varina.
  - [VICTOR ADOLPHUS] SASSERNO, Nice, France, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 23.; ALS. 3 pp. McGregor Library. #38-740.
    Concerning his problems as U. S. Consul. Unable to raise the $2000 bond required of U. S. Consuls. No provision for office expenses in his instructions. Few advantages for maritime commerce at Nice. Mentions Mr. Jackson of New York.
    [1647]
  - CHILION ASHMEAD, Baltimore, to NELSON BARKSDALE, Charlottesville., 1819, March 24.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Application for painting and glazing work at University. Benjamin H. Latrobe will recommend him. Cannot send proposals until he gets price book from Alexandria, Va.
    [1648]
  - CURTIS CARTER and W. B. PHILLIPS, Richmond, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 24.; LS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Terms for bricklaying at the University of Virginia.
    [1649]
  - WILLIAM HAWLEY, JR., Winchester, to NELSON BARKSDALE, Charlottesville., 1819 March 24.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Terms for painting, glazing, and paper hanging at the University of Virginia.
    [1650]
  - R. SCHAER, Washington, D. C., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 March 25.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Offers to sell philosophical apparatus and collection of minerals, shells, antiques, and books to the University of Virginia.
    [1651]
  - WILLIAM T. GRAY, Fredericksburg, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 26.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Another MS. in DLC. #2737-a.
    Recommends Thomas Smith, painter.
    [1652]
  - E. W. HUDNALL, Buckingham County, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 26.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Submits terms for painting and glazing. Can be recommended by Littlebury Moon, Charles Irving, George Booker, Alexander Trent, and William Perkins.
    [1653]
  - NORBORNE RATCLIFFE, Richmond, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 26.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Proposal for brickwork at the University of Virginia.
    [1654]
  - RICHARD WARE, Charlottesville, to NELSON BARKSDALE., 1819 March 26.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Proposal to undertake carpenters' work below prices in Matthew Carey's price book of 1812.
    [1655]
  - JOHN ADAMS, Richmond, to JAMES BRECKENRIDGE., 1819 March 27.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Recommends Russell Dudley, a carpenter, associate of Otis Manson, architect, for work at the University.
    [1656]
  - JAMES DINSMORE, Charlottesville, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 27.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Construction of the University of Virginia. Wage scale set by Matthew Carey's price book unfair.
    [1657]
  - JAMES DINSMORE and JOHN M. PERRY to the BOARD OF VISITORS, UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA., 1819 March 27.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Report on the springs in the University grounds.
    [1658]
  - JAMES OLDHAM, Charlottesville, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia., 1819 March 27.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Terms for doing carpentry work at the University.
    [1659]
  - JOHN M. PERRY to BOARD OF VISITORS, UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA., 1819 March 27.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Submits estimate on brickwork and carpentry at the University. Mentions M[atthew] Brown, and Matthew Carey's Philadelphia Price Book.
    [1660]
  - DABNEY COSBY, Charlottesville, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia., 1819 March 29.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Terms for brickwork at the University.
    [1661]
  - JOHN PERCIVAL, to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., 1819 March 29.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Terms for carpentry work. Objects to scale set in Matthew Carey's price book.
    [1662]
  - THOMAS SMITH, Charlottesville, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia., 1819 March 29.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Proposals for painting, glazing. Returning to Fredericksburg until news of proposal announced.
    [1663]
  - ABRAHAM WOGLOME, Philadelphia, to NELSON BARKSDALE, University of Virginia., 1819 March 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    In response to advertisement in Philadelphia Democratic Press, submits proposals for brickwork.
    [1664]
  - DANIEL R. CALVERLY, [Richmond], to [THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello]., [1819 March ].; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Submits proposal for painting, glazing.
    [1665]
  - JAMES DINSMORE and JOHN M. PERRY, University of Virginia, to NELSON BARKSDALE., 1819 April 1.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Withdrawing earlier proposals. Will work for terms in Matthew Carey's price book.
    [1666]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to THOMAS COOPER, Philadelphia., 1819 April 2.; ALS. 2 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Decision of Visitors to open classical school under usher to be named by Cooper, perhaps Mr. Stack. Will serve as nursery for the University. Need for tinsmith and silversmith in Charlottesville. Plan for the University seal.
    [1667]
  - JOHN NEILSON, Upper Bremo, to BOARD OF VISITORS, University of Virginia., 1819 April 3.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.
    Regrets that he must decline further carpenter's work at present.
    [1668]
  - JAMES OLDHAM, Charlottesville, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1819 April 3.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2737-a.